<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Jake's Blog</title>
 <link href="http://jakesyl.github.io//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://jakesyl.github.io//"/>
 <updated>2014-07-17T12:08:11-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://jakesyl.github.io/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Jake </name>
   <email></email>
 </author>


 <entry>
   <title>One Month Rails Depth</title>
   <link href="http://jakesyl.github.io//2014/07/13/One-Month-Rails-Depth/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://jakesyl.github.io//2014/07/13/One-Month-Rails-Depth</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey Guys,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a one week cruise internet free, I am continuing &lt;a href=&quot;https://onemonth.com/courses/one-month-rails&quot;&gt;One Month Rails&lt;/a&gt; training course and have some more feedback.  It&amp;#39;s getting a  bit boring in terms of content.  Also Mattan doesn&amp;#39;t explain much of ruby, just rails and most of this course is blindly typing.  Anyway, before anything else I would like to show the structure of the one month rails gets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Structure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/Photos/oms.png&quot; alt=&quot;A look inside a video&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic structure is a video above embedded using the less than popular Wistia video hosting service.  Under that are tiny snippets of codes with explanations above.  The only problem I have with this approach is it doesn&amp;#39;t make the student type in the code themselves.  As our teachers have pointed out so many times, the best way to remember something is to write it down.  Then again with new users, a missing &amp;#39;;&amp;#39; in the code can cause what would be a great programmer to give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the video summaries , today, in about an hour I went from the start of day 12, until the 1st video of day 14.  Not my most productive day, but I was working on other projects before this.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 12&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 12 was extremely boring and repetitive, it consisted of pasting several snippets of code I could&amp;#39;ve written myself in LESS from the Bootsrap website. Obviously not the best use of time, but perhaps a good intro to Bootstrap.  Another odd thing is day 12 totaled, with it&amp;#39;s one video 9 minutes.  A more even distribution of time would be far more attractive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 13&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first module in day 13 was entitled &amp;quot;Going online with heroku&amp;quot;.  After my last hackathon, I was extremely weary of heroku.  After building and testing our entire application with mysql, we uploaded it to heroku to discover that their default sql database was postgre and that the mysql database they had provided was bearly adequate to handle a shopping list let alone the large databases our project required.  In any case, I decided to jump back on the Heroku band wagon for the one month rails tutorial, after several minutes of configuring the production file, I was online.  I was a bit shocked at how fast it went, as the people who I had talked to constantly complained about how slow rails initialization was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next module, as you can see below was a space where you entered your Heroku app name, nothing special, and probably unnecesary considering the fact that they already had my git repository from earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Final module of &amp;quot;Day 13&amp;quot;, I skipped as it was about registering a custom domain name which has almost no purpose, especially when your creating a clone of a website that already exsists.  However as I suspected Mattan is earning additional revenue through his &amp;quot;special deal&amp;quot; (an affiliate link)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 14&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 14 brought me back to my days of wordpress and plugins.  Instead of writing database interaction to sign up users amongst other things, we used a gem called devise.  Devise adds full functionality of user signups, encryption and other features that I haven&amp;#39;t had the pleasure to explore yet.  Here&amp;#39;s a picture of the courses from day 12 to day 14:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/Photos/day12-14.png&quot; alt=&quot;Days 12-14 of One Month Rails&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It appears that from here until day 18 is basically modifications and further setup for devise, upon looking through the source code I have realized that this is quite a complicated gem, and if I could read ruby, I would be quite interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jake&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>

 <entry>
   <title>More on One Month Rails</title>
   <link href="http://jakesyl.github.io//2014/06/26/More-One-Month-Info/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://jakesyl.github.io//2014/06/26/More-One-Month-Info</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey Guys,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending several hours and making it through 7 &amp;quot;days&amp;quot; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://onemonth.com/courses/one-month-rails&quot;&gt;One Month Rails&lt;/a&gt; I have a bit more to blabber about.  Honestly, I&amp;#39;m really starting to like Rails.  I think it&amp;#39;s a really good language, and I look forward to learning more about it and eventually to learning Ruby.  So More on what I did in these &amp;quot;days&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 7 was extremely easy, all I did was create 2 pages (home and about) and link them to each other.  The pages were home and about, and this was done using the command line (which I found rather interesting) using &lt;code&gt;rails generate controller pages home about&lt;/code&gt;.  This simple command created two pages, Home and about, of course I still had to route and define both the pages.  This was easy except for the fact that finding the files to edit took about 20 minutes.  In the next video we just used embedded ruby to make a link... Extremely simple.  Additionally in these videos he taught some, but very little html such as &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 8 and 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 8 was a simple, 9 minute manner of placing erb (embedded ruby links) in the header of the layouts folder.  Day 9 was a matter of installing bootstrap (sass not less), importing and restarting a server.
&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/Photos/day7-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;Days 7 through 9&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 10 and 11&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the fact that most, if not all people reading this are web designers I&amp;#39;ll skip the details of day 8, basically using SASS bootstrap we added a default navbar and changed some text, very simple put together in an elegant 17 minute video.  A little long, but one month did an excellent job of explaining css pre-proccesors to new web developers.  Day 11 was simply setting some Sass variables in a bootstrap file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/Photos/day10-11.png&quot; alt=&quot;Days 10 and 11&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jake&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>

 <entry>
   <title>My first day of rails</title>
   <link href="http://jakesyl.github.io//2014/06/25/rails-start/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://jakesyl.github.io//2014/06/25/rails-start</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey Guys,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an experienced developer, and taking a pretty base level course, I wanted to give some feedback as to how I did in day 1 through day 6 of &lt;a href=&quot;https://onemonth.com/courses/one-month-rails&quot;&gt;One Month Rails&lt;/a&gt; (Even though I&amp;#39;ve only actually been doing Rails for about an hour).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first day is an intro/overview (totaling 3 minutes) and the much more lengthy installing rails.  Luckily for me, I already  had rails installed, however they did post a great resource called &lt;a href=&quot;installrails.com&quot;&gt;Install Rails&lt;/a&gt; that I genuinely wish I had when I was installing rails.  The website is intuitive and beautifully designed, they finish with a sanity check which details two ways to check your installations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;ruby -v
rails -v
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fairly simple stuff in case you were wondering, this is what day 1 curriculum looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/Photos/day1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Day 1 Videos&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see it&amp;#39;s a fairly nice website presumably built in rails (it would be funny if the website was built in PHP)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 2 was boring me to tears, in day 2 you learn about &amp;quot;the command line&amp;quot;.  After spending several minutes teaching us how to open terminal he proceeds to show us the &amp;#39;pwd&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;ls&amp;#39;, and &amp;#39;cd&amp;#39; commands, all of which I use on a daily basis.  However as with before, were I a complete beginer I would have found his explanation  extremely helpful.  The second and last video was common sense in addition to 100% true.  It was titled: &amp;quot;Debugging&amp;quot; 75% of code is googling.  A 4 minute example of him solving rvm (ruby version manager) errors by going on stack overflow and a Google group, once again quite boring.  It would be nice if some of these sites let you select your skill level to skip some of the basic, generic stuff (kind of like how whenever you learn a new programming language, you have to listen to the lecturer spent half an hour explaining the difference between a &amp;#39;float&amp;#39; and a &amp;#39;double&amp;#39;).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 3 had one video entitled &amp;quot;Creating a new Application&amp;quot;, it walked through the basics of creating a ruby project with the command line, and accessing the local server, still a little slow for my pace, but more along the lines of what I like in terms of pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 4 and Day 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve condensed these because it seemed a little redundant talking about them on Github, these two days go over the basics of setting up git on your local computer, I skipped all of these except a cool form asking me for my Github URL.  It&amp;#39;s worth mentioning that for the tutorial one month rails went with terminal over GUI.  This is what I do, but it is a rather strange choice for a &amp;quot;first coding class&amp;quot; website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Days 2-4 Assignments:
&lt;img src=&quot;/Photos/day2-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Days 2 through 4 Videos&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I start learning what I signed up for, Rails, in this short two video day, I created a home page, and an about page.  Interestingly enough these pages were suffixed with .html.erb  HTML for what it would be rendered to erb to signify the need for rendering.  I also had to rout all these pages to a specific url, vs just folder placement.  This was definitely a different and new experience.  I&amp;#39;m assuming on build it will build folders according to routing instructions.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: &amp;#39;by Today I mean Day x not today as in June 25th&amp;#39;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Days 5-6 Assignments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/Photos/day5-6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Days 5 through 6 Videos&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bold look ahead at Day 7 reveals I will be creating dynamic pages.  In a rendered language like Ruby I am wondering how this is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for Reading,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jake&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Sorry for being a bit above everything, this is just extremely boring&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>

 <entry>
   <title>Why I decided to learn rails</title>
   <link href="http://jakesyl.github.io//2014/06/24/rails/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://jakesyl.github.io//2014/06/24/rails</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey guys,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve decided to learn Ruby on Rails over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://onemonth.com/courses/one-month-rails/&quot;&gt;One Month Rails&lt;/a&gt;. As I said in my last post; I&amp;#39;m a PHP guy. I&amp;#39;ve contributed to Wordpress and every website I&amp;#39;ve ever made I&amp;#39;ve made entirely in PHP.  However, seeing the increasing number of websites made in Rails, and fearing that PHP will become as useless as Perl (no offense) I realized I need to learn.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is about why I chose to learn let&amp;#39;s look at the reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitters beautiful, Facebook/Wikipedia not so much&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easier to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large increase in popularity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terminal looks really, really cool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Superior run times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruby is more like Perl in that TMTOWTDI (There&amp;#39;s more than one way to do it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More Deployable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Better for web startups&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Bad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruby is ranked hardest to learn by Udemy, below Python and PHP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP has higher performance compared to Ruby (no web framework)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP has 21% of all programming job postings compared to 3% on ruby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources:
* &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/PROGRAMMING-LANGUAGE-3.png&quot;&gt; Udemy Infographic&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amzur.com/comparison-php-vs-ruby-on-rails-ror/&quot;&gt; Amzur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I&amp;#39;m being extremely biased, in order to convince myself to shell out the $100 I do think that Ruby is going to be the future of the internet.  The reality is PHP is just old, It&amp;#39;s based off C++ and there&amp;#39;s no expression.  Although I&amp;#39;m saying this now, I&amp;#39;ll see if my opinion changes in 30 days.  Now a lovely infographic that well explains the opinions of some fanboys I know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/Photos/fanboys.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Forus Gump&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>

 <entry>
   <title>Hello World!</title>
   <link href="http://jakesyl.github.io//2014/01/02/Hello-World/"/>
   <updated>2014-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://jakesyl.github.io//2014/01/02/Hello-World</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, my name is Jake!  I&amp;#39;m a young developer and high school student who&amp;#39;s now hosting his blog on &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://getpoole.com&quot;&gt;Poole&lt;/a&gt;.  Although many, of my friends know about my out of school activities on github: I&amp;#39;m going to keep my last name out of the blog for a while.  So hello there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why I chose Poole&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m a wordpress kid, I&amp;#39;ve been using wordpress since early 2005, I&amp;#39;ve used it for literally everything: Social websites, Forums, Wiki&amp;#39;s, Blogs, Homepages and even as a base for a node.js search engine I wrote.  I&amp;#39;ve implemented java plugins and everything else into them, so why switch now?  The versatility that once made wordpress my best friend is now it&amp;#39;s worst feature.  I can&amp;#39;t count the number of wordpress based sites that have gone haywire because I messed up a single line of code in a plugin; or worse someone else did.  Having to constantly fix errors made me part of a community, but it took me away from the things I wanted to do.  Some other problems I had with wordpress were&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Disadvantages of Wordpress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Far too backend heavy, I kept going over my cpu allocation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third party themes with plugins built-in that shouldn&amp;#39;t be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standard features doing the job of plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of simplicity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last reason was probably the biggest, I got so caught up in modifying the code, I never ended up writing, hopefully github blogs can fix that.  I also realize that most of these are indicators of my laziness, and it&amp;#39;s true.  I could extremely easily fix all of this myself, but it would take me away from what I wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So thanks for visiting my blog!  I am going to try to update it whenever I can however, as old habits die hard I am probably going to end up screwing around with the code adding ever addon I can make for a while.  Also, in case you noticed I wrote this post on the format of the lanyon post, I need it as a reference for this new markup languages, although this is very similiar to wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>


</feed>
